

FREDERICK HINTON MACON

Dedicated Customer Service Specialist providing skills to prioritize and multi-task in fast-paced working environment. Successfully works as part of team to reach personal and business goals. Known for successfully handling escalated customer support issues. Resourceful and client focused Customer Service Manager with over 8 years of experience leading teams in exceeding sales goals and customer expectations. Meticulous and results-oriented with expertise educating employees on all stages of sales cycle while recommending best options to meet short- and long-term needs. Personable relationship builder with polished communications skills.

OBJECTIVE

To get started right away, just tap any placeholder text (such as this) and start typing to replace it with your own.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Client relations and retention Product Knowledge Training and coaching

EXPERIENCE

MEDICAL DATA SYSTEMS

FEB. 2022 TO CURRENT

Developed and maintained a tracking system of incoming and late payments. Initiate late payment notices to relevant parties. Negotiate repayments and financial plans as needed.

Walmart-Melbourne, FL

May 2016 to Jun 2020

Customer Service Manager

Established positive rapport with customers, managers and customer service team members to maintain positive and successful work environment. Maintained knowledge of company products and services to promptly resolve complaints and concerns. Assisted staff with resolving complex customer issues and implementing targeted solutions. Scanned and bagged items and operated cash register to check out store patrons. Created eye-catching merchandise displays to entice customers into store. Monitored performance of sales team and implemented improved methods to close gaps. Received shipments, signed off on packages and documented incoming items in computer system. Cross-trained on different positions to best support team during peak periods. Achieved sales targets regularly to enable sustained growth. Kept customers engaged with positive, sales-minded attitude demonstrating pride in products Delivered fast, friendly and knowledgeable service for routine questions and service complaints. Assisted customers in making payments on accounts and setting up payment plans. Upheld strict quality control policies and procedures during customer interactions. Oversaw and assessed customer service staff activities to provide personnel with regular performance-related feedback. Responded to in-person and online customers to improve company customer service ratings. Assessed departmental operations to determine areas for customer service improvement and support. Supported operational improvements and resolution of problems to deliver top-notch customer service. Led team engaged in delivering assistance to customer service department on daily basis.

FREDERICK HINTON MACON

DEDICATED CUSTOMER SERVICE SPECIALIST PROVIDING SKILLS TO PRIORITIZE AND MULTI-TASK IN **FAST-PACED** WORKING ENVIRONMENT. SUCCESSFULLY WORKS AS PART OF TEAM TO REACH PERSONAL AND BUSINESS GOALS. KNOWN FOR SUCCESSFULLY HANDLING ESCALATED CUSTOMER SUPPORT ISSUES. RESOURCEFUL AND CLIENT **FOCUSED CUSTOMER SERVICE** MANAGER WITH OVER 8 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE LEADING TEAMS IN EXCEEDING SALES GOALS AND CUSTOMER EXPECTATIONS. METICULOUS AND RESULTS-**ORIENTED WITH EXPERTISE EDUCATING EMPLOYEES ON ALL** STAGES OF SALES CYCLE WHILE **RECOMMENDING BEST OPTIONS** TO MEET SHORT- AND LONG-TERM NEEDS. PERSONABLE RELATIONSHIP BUILDER WITH POLISHED COMMUNICATIONS SKILLS.

Speedway Gas Station

May 2012 to Oct 2016

Senior Sales Associate

Built and maintained new and established client relationships with exceptional communication, personalized interactions and friendly attentive service. Operated point of sale equipment and returned cash, coin, payment cards and receipts to clients. Mentored new sales team members on company standards, customer service techniques and effective sales strategies. Processed payments and returned accurately receipts, cash, coin and cards to customers. Checked store shelves and restocked products from inventory in back room. Greeted patrons warmly at store entrance and helped with finding needed items. Delivered quality customer service while cultivating client satisfaction and loyalty.

7 Eleven Gas Station-Melbourne, FL

Nov 2006 to May 2012

Senior Sales Associate

Cultivated a customer-focused shopping environment by greeting and responding to all customers in a friendly manner. Communicated clear expectations and goals to each team member. Worked with the management team to implement the proper division of responsibilities. Maintained established merchandising standards, including window, sales floor and promotional displays. Stocked and replenished merchandise according to store merchandising layouts. Priced merchandise, stocked shelves and took inventory of supplies. Cleaned and organized the store, including the checkout desk and displays. Completed all point of sale opening and closing procedures, including counting the contents of the cash register. Trained new sales associates each quarter. Assisted sales manager in creating detailed plan-o-grams to maximize space and optimize display for merchandise. Processed payments and returned accurately receipts, cash, coin and cards to customers. Greeted

FREDERICK HINTON MACON

DEDICATED CUSTOMER SERVICE SPECIALIST PROVIDING SKILLS TO PRIORITIZE AND MULTI-TASK IN **FAST-PACED** WORKING ENVIRONMENT. SUCCESSFULLY WORKS AS PART OF TEAM TO REACH PERSONAL AND BUSINESS GOALS. KNOWN FOR SUCCESSFULLY HANDLING ESCALATED CUSTOMER SUPPORT ISSUES. RESOURCEFUL AND CLIENT FOCUSED CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER WITH OVER 8 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE LEADING TEAMS IN EXCEEDING SALES GOALS AND CUSTOMER EXPECTATIONS. METICULOUS AND RESULTS-**ORIENTED WITH EXPERTISE EDUCATING EMPLOYEES ON ALL** STAGES OF SALES CYCLE WHILE **RECOMMENDING BEST OPTIONS** TO MEET SHORT- AND LONG-TERM NEEDS. PERSONABLE RELATIONSHIP BUILDER WITH POLISHED COMMUNICATIONS SKILLS.

patrons warmly at store entrance and offered assistance with finding needed items.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

High School Diploma

Starkville High School May 2001

Starkville, MS

University of Central Florida

UX/UI Design Bootcamp

November 2021-June 1, 2022